PAULA GEEVES-BOOTH - SOFTWARE ENGINEER

West New York, NJ | 310-736-8255 | pngeeves@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub

SUMMARY

Full-Stack software engineer proficient in using Javascript for front-end and back-end programming, React, HTML, CSS, API implementing, Node.JS, Express, PostgreSQL, and frameworks like Bootstrap. Past experience with a major international retail company, providing a first-hand insight to proper site optimization for user experience, as well as the possible bugs and issues when dealing with a high-traffic website, especially during the peak holiday season and high-profile product launch events.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Frontend: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, jQuery.

Backend: Node.js, Express, RESTful APIs, PostgreSQL.

Tools: Mocha, Chai, Knex, Git, GitHub, Heroku, Node Package Manager, Visual Studio Code.

Additional Skills: Project Management, Financial and Sales Forecasting, Supplier Negotiations, Client Relations

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING PROJECTS

Restaurant Reservation Application | Project Link

09/2022

- Full stack reservation and table management system.
- Implemented react router and express to build a RESTful API in order to make HTTP requests for all of the reservation data stored on the connected PostgreSQL database.
- Created CRUD functions and knex queries to handle data going to and coming from the database.
- Used Git to track changes and versions while keeping sensitive information from being pushed to repositories.
- Technology: React, Node.js, Express, Knex and PostgreSQL.

Movie Database Application | Project Link

08/2022

- Assembled the back end of a movie website allowing any user to search for their favorite movies.
- Used CRUD methods for reviews, and view theaters and movies that are showing.
- Applied router and controller functions to retrieve a user's specific requests.
- Technology: Node.js, Express, and Knex. Version control with Git.

Study Tool Application | Project Link

07/2022

- Created an application that allows users to create, edit, and delete decks and cards within them.
- Created a REST API and middleware functions to allow user(s) to create, read, update and delete their perfect deck of study cards.
- Defined routes and URLs, and used state over multiple components.
- Technology: JavaScript, React, Express, Knex, HTML and CSS. Progress/Versions tracked with Git.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Walmart Inc.

Bentonville, AK

04/2020 - 03/2021

- Associate Merchant | Video Game Accessories
 - Negotiated with brand partners on implementing launch strategies, maintaining store and online assortments, and ensuring Walmart has the lowest price among its competitors.
 - Collaborated with the software engineering team to troubleshoot and delegate a quick fix for daily issues escalating from the Walmart website.
 - Increased monthly sales by 400% by working closely with merchandising teams to navigate the extreme increase in customer spending habits due to Covid-19, enabling the company to stay in-stock of popular products compared to competitors.

The Upper-Deck Company

Carlsbad, CA

Entertainment & E-Sports Marketing Intern

12/2018 - 06/2019

- Accompanied the talent relations department to Blizzard Arena to work one-on-one with Esports athletes to assist in acquisition of signatures and coordination of merchandise.
- Wrote and edited creative briefs and coordinated with other departments for online marketing materials.
- Engaged with e-sports fans both in person and online during the debut launch of OverWatch League trading cards, exceeding pre-sales expectations by over 200%.

EDUCATION

Thinkful Online

Certificate, Software Engineering Program

03/2022 - 09/2022

• Learned industry best practices and software development standards with a focus on Javascript, HTML5, CSS3, React Native, Node.js, PostgreSQL, RESTful APIs, algorithms, and data structures.

 Developed and deployed mobile-first applications while learning new languages and frameworks, spending several hours per week collaborating with and learning from senior web developers in a mentor-student relationship.

University of California, San Diego
B.A., Communications and Media | GPA: 3.7

San Diego, CA 06/2019